今なら まだ
Not yet…
今なら…
Now…
Now that there is hardly anyone with PK left…
ＰＫが途絶える今なら…
Five hundred and
seventy years
later
Kanto
歴史を…
We can change…
…history!
変える！
狙うは 慈光帝のみ！
Spare all but the Emperor of Merciful Light!
やあっ！
The False Minoshiro
Episode Three
Saki, help me with the rowing!
早季 ちゃんと こげよ
I’m doing all I can!
ちゃ～んと こいでるわよ！
You need to stick to my rhythm!
そっちが合わせないんでしょ！
Man, how are those two doing it so much better?
One thousand
years later
Ibaraki
Tone River
あ～あ あっちの組と
なんで こんなに違うんだ？
きゃはっ キレイ～
It’s so pretty!
よく見てよ
Look at them.
Mamoru’s pacing himself to row like Maria.
守が しっかり真理亜に
合わせてるでしょ？
前の人間は
後ろが見えないんだから
The front rower has to keep their eyes forward.
You have to stick to my rhythm.
そっちが合わせてくんないと
あっちは 前で真理亜が
The difference is that Maria’s rowing properly!
きちんと こいでるから
合わせられんだ
You’re just staring at the scenery instead of rowing!
お前は景色ばっか見てて
全然 こいでねぇじゃねぇか
何してんの！
What are you doing?
川って 気持ちいいよな～
Rivers are so nice…
海みたいに しぶきが
塩っからくないしさ～
The river spray’s not salty like ocean water.
呪力には頼らないで
Weren’t you telling us all to row as far as possible without using our Canti?
行けるところまで こぐって
言い張ってたのは あんたでしょ？
もう あきらめたの？
Have you given up already?
バッカだな～
川下りじゃねぇんだから
Get real.
We’re going upstream.
We can’t make it just by rowing.
手で こいで
逆上れる訳ねぇじゃん
本物？
カヤノスヅクリのじゃなくて？
Are you sure it’s not just a haythatcher nest?
本物だよ 巣のふちで分かるんだ
It’s the real thing.
The shape of the nest gives it away.
ふ～ん
This one would be a haythatcher’s.
カヤノスヅクリのは これだ
Demon's Hand
Hey, don’t eat it yet!
こら 食べちゃダメ！
Cooking it like this will…
アッハッハ…
You’re good at drawing, Mamoru.
It’ll taste the same anyway!
I can do better!
風船犬？
Blowdogs?
そんなの いる訳ないじゃん
They aren’t real. Don’t be ridiculous.
それが 本当なんだって
つい最近 見た人がいるんだよ
I’m serious.
Someone’s seen one recently.
見た人って 誰？
Who’s that someone?
名前は知らないけどさ…
I don’t know the name…
See, he’s fibbing, as usual.
ほら いつものことよ
証人がいるとか
それが誰かってなると コレよコレ
He always claims there are witnesses,
but when you ask who it is, this is all you get.
でも 聞いたら多分
名前は 分かると思うよ
I’m pretty sure I can get his name if I just ask.
その人は筑波山に行った時に
麓近くで 風船犬を見たんだって
He saw a blowdog when he went up Mount Tsukuba.
筑波山？ その人は そんな所まで
何しに行ったの？
Mount Tsukuba? Why did he go there?
He was looking into something for the Board of Education.
教育委員会の仕事で
何か調査に行ったらしいんだ
詳しい事は
子供には教えてくれないけど
They won’t tell children anything specific.
…んで 麓にさしかかった時
So, at the foot of the mountain,
a blowdog came out of a big cave.
大きな横穴から
風船犬が はい出してきたんだって
風船犬って どんななの？
What does a blowdog look like?
It’s about as big as a normal dog, but pitch black.
普通の犬くらいの大きさで
まっ黒なんだって
胴体は太いのに 頭は犬の
半分くらいの大きさしかなくて
Its trunk is pretty bulky, but its head is about half the size of a dog’s,
and its legs are so short
its belly almost touches the ground.
地面すれすれに ついてるらしい
本当に犬なの？
Is it really a dog?
Who knows? It probably isn’t.
どうかな？ 多分 違うと思うけど
あんまり危険そうじゃないわね
It doesn’t sound very dangerous.
うん でも怒らせると風船みたいに
大きく膨れていくんだ
Yeah, but it swells up like a balloon if you provoke it.
If you back off, you’re good,
その段階で
相手が引き下がれば いいんだけど
but if you make it really angry…
もしも 限界を超えて怒らせると…
Let me guess. It keeps swelling up until it explodes, right?
そのまま どんどん膨れていって
最後には爆発するんでしょ？
言ってて バカバカしくないの？
Does this really not sound dumb to you?
See, that’s the catch!
そこなんだよ 問題は！
え？
Doesn’t this completely defy common sense?
あまりにも話が とっぴというか
奇想天外だろ？
だますために
作り話を広めようと思ったら
Wouldn’t you come up with a more believable story if you wanted to scare everyone?
もっとさ いかにもありそうな話に
すると思わねえか？
でも それは あり得ないと思うな
But it still sounds unrealistic.
Why?
何でだよ
Well, its own self-defense mechanism would kill itself first.
だって 脅しを実行に移したら
自分が先に死んじゃうんだろ？
そんなことしてたら 風船犬は
すぐに死に絶えちゃうよ
Blowdogs would be extinct in no time.
そうそう
その人は 風船犬を見た後で
Back to the story!
After seeing the blowdog, this person also encountered an evil minoshiro.
悪魔のミノシロに会ったんだって
そうそうって もしもし？
“Back to the story”? Seriously?
風船犬の件は
どうなったんでしょうか？
What about the blowdog?
He came across it on the way up Mount Tsukuba.
筑波山に登る途中 遭遇したんだ
悪魔のミノシロって
ミノシロモドキのこと？
An evil minoshiro? You mean a false minoshiro?
うん 一見
ミノシロそっくりなんだけど
Yeah. At first sight it looks just like a minoshiro,
よく見ると 結構 違うらしい
but upon closer inspection, it’s quite different.
何で悪魔なの？
Why the “evil” part?
悪魔のミノシロに出会った人間は
遠からず 死ぬことになるからだよ
Because all who’ve met one have died soon after!
So has this witness died too? I bet he hasn’t.
じゃあ その人は死んじゃったの？
死んでないんでしょ？ どうせ
He’s probably going to die soon.
もうすぐ 死ぬんじゃないかな
Want to make that our topic for the trip?
夏季キャンプの課題
それにしない？
What do you mean?
それ？ どれ？
悪魔のミノシロのこと？
You mean the evil minoshiro?
うん それも含めて
Yeah. That and other creatures like blowdogs.
風船犬や 他の生き物も
せっかくの機会だし
I’d like to investigate if those stories are true now that we’re here.
本当にいるのかどうか
確かめてみたい気がする
面白いんじゃない？
Sounds interesting!
ちょっと待てよ
みんな 分かってんのか？
Wait a moment!
You’re forgetting something important.
悪魔のミノシロに出会ったら
死んじゃうかもしれないんだぞ
You might wind up dead if you see an evil minoshiro.
死ぬわけないわよ
No way that’s true.
でも どうやって捕まえんだよ
あっ… 言い忘れてたけど
So how are you going to catch one?
Oh, I forgot to mention this, but apparently
your Cantus won’t work on an evil minoshiro.
悪魔のミノシロには
呪力が効かないらしいんだよ
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
う～ん… 呪力が効かないっていう
状態が よく分からないな
I’m not sure how your Cantus could be ineffective against something.
どんな状態？
How would that work?
説明して
Elaborate!
Hey, want to go night rowing?
ねえ ナイトカヌーやらない？
That sounds good! Let’s do it!
ああ！ それいいわね やるやる
危なくない？
Isn’t that a bit dangerous?
何よ いつもは威勢がいいくせに
怖いの？
Where has all your usual courage gone?
Are you scared?
怖くなんかねぇよ
何 言ってんだよ…
I’m not!
What are you talking about?
気をつければ大丈夫だよ
早季は どう？
That’s not even what I meant.
We should be fine if we’re careful.
What do you think, Saki?
え？ …うん
Huh?
I agree.
決まりだ
It’s decided, then.
じゃあ クジ引きしよう
Let’s draw lots.
火の番なんてヤだよ！
I don’t wanna watch the fire!
クジ引きだから
しょうがないでしょ
We drew lots! You have to accept the results.
灯台の役目は大事だよ
Watching the fire is a big responsibility.
ふざけんなっ！
The hell it is!
Have fun!
Don’t look at the fire.
たき火の方 見ちゃダメだよ
Not like the fire will go out if we’re gone anyway!
Why?
どうして？
It’s a basic tenet of night rowing.
What if it does? It’d be really scary!
ナイトカヌーの鉄則だよ
This is bull! You could see all the
markings if you looked into the can!
何だよ この缶
上から見たら 丸見えじゃねぇか
誰も見てないわよ
Nobody looked, silly.
残り物には福とか言うから…
Those who stay behind are blessed, they say…
あ～ああ…
Oh man…
こうしてると
Now that it’s dark, it’s hard to know how fast we’re going.
どれぐらいの速さで進んでるのか
分かんなくなるわ
You can tell if you put your hand into the water.
水に手をつけてみれば 分かるよ
It feels so good.
気持ちいい…
結構 速いわね…
We’re going quite fast.
What’s wrong?
どうしたの？
こいでると さざ波が立つだろ？
The rowing puts ripples in the water.
Ready? I’m going to flatten the surface.
いい？ 消してみるよ
すごい…
Wow…
キレイ…
It’s so pretty…
I feel like I’m in space.
宇宙にいるみたい…
そうだね…
Yeah.
そろそろ 戻ろうか？
Want to head back?
Ancient literature contains hardly any mention of the minoshiro.
古代の文献を調べても
ミノシロについて
ほとんど言及されていない
Much of the literature from
a thousand years ago is censored,
1,000年以上
前に刊行された書籍では
多くが 閲覧禁止の措置が
取られているとはいえ
but even so, mention of the minoshiro is practically absent.
｢ミノシロ｣という文字は
まったく発見できない
だとすると ミノシロが
地上に生まれてきたのは
Therefore, it must have come into existence in the last few centuries at most.
せいぜい ここ数百年のうち
ということになるが
進化の常識に照らして
そんなに短期間に
The idea of a new species emerging so quickly is unthinkable.
新しい種が
生まれるとは考えられない
This applies to not only the minoshiro.
これは
ミノシロに限った話ではなく
1,000年前の文明期と現在とでは
フォーナに 大きな断絶が見られる
Since the fall of ancient civilization a thousand years ago, the fauna has changed dramatically.
ミノシロを含む数百種は
Hundreds of species, including the minoshiro, seemingly materialized out of thin air.
突然 天から降って湧いたように
登場しているのだ
近年 新たに提唱された仮説が
主流になりつつある
A different theory has gained wider approval in recent years.
All these species, including the minoshiro, are the result of evolution accelerated by the unconscious of human beings.
ミノシロを含む多くの生き物は
人間の無意識が及ぼす働きで
急激に
進化を加速されたというのである
うわ あ～ち あちあち…
Ouch, it’s hot! It’s hot!
アハハ… ウフフフ…
とっとっとっと…
Hey!
お～い！
もっと スピード上げよう！
Let’s row faster!
Why?
どうして？
このあたりは 調べないの？
Don’t you want to look at what’s around here?
I’ve seen enough.
パス パス パス！
どうせ 大したのいないよ
There’s probably nothing interesting.
でも もう少し行った所で
But we’re nearly at the campsite
indicated on the plans we turned in.
今晩のテント張るって
計画表 出したよ？
何 言ってんだよ
Oh, please.
このキャンプの本当のテーマを
忘れちゃったのか？
Have you forgotten the real reason we’re here?
We’re here to find evil minoshiros and blowdogs!
悪魔のミノシロと風船犬だぜ？
Come on, let’s leave Lake Kasumigaura behind and make landfall somewhere.
いいから さっさと
霞ヶ浦を突っ切って 上陸しようぜ
う～ん… 先生は
Um… But the teachers told us not to go too far in.
奥まで行っちゃいけないって
言ってたでしょう？
And we really shouldn’t land on the other side.
それに やっぱり上陸するなんて…
大丈夫だって
ちょっと上がって ぱっと見て
Don’t worry.
We’ll just land, take a quick look, and come right back.
すぐ戻ってくるだけだから
What do you think, Shun?
どうする？ 瞬
It’s true that we’d be in trouble if anyone found out.
確かに バレると まずいだろうね
でも 僕は
ちょっと行ってみたい気がする
But, you know, I kind of want to take a look.
ここまで来るチャンスは
もう ないと思うし
I think this is the only chance we’ll get.
ウフ…
All right, decision made!
よし 決まりな！
やったあ
こんなとこまで やって来た！
All right!
Here we are!
We made it.
来たわねぇ
ねぇ
Yup!
おえ～ うっ うう…
よっしゃあ！
All right!
何が！
What is?!
I’m back in business!
ふっか～つ！
あっ どうしたの？
Why the glasses?
Don’t they look cool?
かっこいいじゃない
The light flickering off the water kind of dazzled me.
水面の光を見てたらさ
チカチカしちゃって…
Only cuz you were staring like an idiot.
ボ～ッと見てっからよ～
Shut up!
うるさいわね！
I suggest we carry only light equipment and climb the mountainside.
とりあえず 軽く背負えるだけ
持って 登ってみようか？
行こう！ 行こう！
Hell, yeah! Let’s go!
見晴らしの いいところで
お弁当 食べよう
Let’s eat somewhere with a nice view.
Food…
お弁当
うっ… いった！
Ouch!
蚊！ 蚊
It was a mosquito!
いっぱい いるわよ～
There are so many of them!
もう や～
I’ve had enough…
何 これ？
What’s this?
It looks like… a shrine.
多分… 神社だ
神社？
A shrine?
2,000年～3,000年位の歴史が
あった 由緒ある神社らしいよ
I think this shrine has a history of
about two or three thousand years.
ここで お弁当 食べる？
Want to eat here?
わっ！ あ…
どうしたの？
What’s wrong?
悪魔の… ミノシロ…
An evil… minoshiro…
あっ！ 早く！
覚… 瞬… 捕まえて！
Quick!
Satoru, Shun! Catch it!
It’s going to get away!
逃げちゃう！ え…？
Hey… Hey!
ちょっと… えっ？
ねえ！
わたしたち… 死ぬのかしら
Are we going to die?
I don’t think that part of the story is true.
あの話だったら
多分 ウソだって…
Why couldn’t I move?
何で 動けなかったのかな？
I couldn’t either.
わたしも… えっ 何で？ 覚？
What do you think, Satoru?
Beats me.
分かんねえ あの光を見てたら
ボ～っとしてきて…
When I saw the light, my mind went completely blank.
I couldn’t use my Cantus either.
呪力が使えなかった
うん？
あのときの感じ…
That feeling…
Remember? The feeling when you looked into the flames at the Temple of Purity…
ほら 清浄寺で
護摩壇の炎を見つめてたとき
I see… I get it now.
そっか…
そうだ さっきのは催眠術なんだ
We were hypnotized just now.
何 それ？
What’s that?
It’s an ancient way of controlling someone else’s mind.
大昔からある
人の心を操る技術のことだよ
暗示をかけることで
眠らせたり 自白させたり
Through suggestions, you can make someone sleep, tell the truth, or do whatever else you want.
好きなことをさせられるんだ
But Saki was fine, wasn’t she?
でも 早季は 結構 平気だったよな
She even shouted at us to catch it.
｢捕まえろ～｣とか
大声 出してたしさ
鈍感なんじゃねえ？
She must be really thick-headed.
違うわよ！
No, I’m not!
That’s enough, Satoru.
やめろって 覚
んだよ！
What?!
Let it rest.
まあ いいから
いくねえだろ
It had no effect on her!
Don’t you think it’s because of the sunglasses?
サングラス
かけてたからじゃない？
These?
これ？
That might be it.
そうかも…
赤いガラスで効果が半減したとか
Perhaps the red glasses shield you somehow.
ちょっと 見せて
うん
Can I see them?
Okay.
あいつに呪力を使えるのが
早季だけだとすると
Catching it might be a bit tough if Saki’s
the only one who can use her Cantus on it.
捕まえるのは
厳しいかもしれないな
Yeah.
It seems to hide in those holes a lot.
今みたいに 狭い所に
もぐり込むのが好きみたいだし
もう 帰った方がいいんじゃない？
Shouldn’t we head back?
Let’s go back to the canoes then.
じゃあ カヌーの所まで戻ろう
We can do it! We can catch it!
大丈夫！ 捕まえられるわ！
Huh?
ほお～！
Hurry up, Maria!
真理亜！ 早く早く！
分かってるって～
I know, I know!
大漁～！
And… caught!
確かに
何でも食べてるみたいだよね
They sure seem to eat anything.
見つけたら 襲いかかるかもね
They’ll probably attack once they see it.
What if they eat it before we can catch it?
捕まえる前に食っちまったら
どうすんだよ
Don’t say that!
やだあ…
Anyway, I like this idea.
でも
このアイデアは いいと思うよ
瞬
うん？
Shun.
You take Saki’s side a lot, don’t you?
お前
やけに早季のこと かばうよな
そうかな
Do I?
Would you be quiet? I’m trying to concentrate here!
集中できないから
変なこと 言わないでよ
You’re unbelievable…
何だ コイツ…
また 何か捕まえたわ！
大きそう
They’ve got something!
Looks like something big!
引っ張り出してみろよ
Then pull them out.
手伝ってよ！
Help us!
You can do it yourself.
自分で できんだろ？
呪力で つたを引くだけなんだから
Just pull the ropes using your Cantus.
だって 気持ち悪いじゃない
But this is so creepy!
あっ あ？
じゃあ 僕がやるよ
Then I’ll do it.
あっ あれ？
捕まえたんじゃないか？
Look, they’ve got it.
瞬… 覚… 捕まえて！
Shun! Satoru! Catch it!
破壊行為をやめてください
Please cease your destructive activity.
あなたが損壊しているのは
You are damaging public library property.
Who’s this?
誰？
公共の財産である
図書館の備品です
今すぐに
破壊行為をやめてください
Please cease your destructive activity at once.
Huh?
Please cease your destructive activity.
破壊行為をやめてください
あっ あ… あんたが
変な催眠術かけるからよ！
Th-Th-Then you stop using your weird hypnosis!
光による幻惑は
端末機械の自己防衛策として
The use of light hypnosis by
terminal machines for self-defense
法令488722 5項によって
認められています
is sanctioned by ordinance 488722, clause 5.
今すぐに
破壊行為をやめてください
Please cease your destructive activity at once.
You stop first! Then I’ll stop ripping them out!
そっちが やめたら
私だって引き抜いたりしないわ！
I repeat my warning.
重ねて警告します 今すぐに
破壊行為をやめてください
Please cease your destructive activity at once.
こっちも警告するわ！
I’m warning you too!
そっちが やめなきゃ
こっちも やめないわよ！
If you don’t stop, neither will I!
I’ll tear all those glowing things off you!
その光ってるやつを
全部 引き抜いちゃっていいのね？
あっ 大丈夫？
Are you guys okay?
止まった…
It stopped.
You’re amazing, Saki.
早季 すごいね
You don’t have to praise her…
あんたは… 早季のこと
褒めなくていいの
Who are you? What are you?
あんたは誰？ いったい何なの？
私は国立国会図書館 つくば館です
図書館？
I am the Tsukuba branch of the National Assembly Library.
A library?
ミノシロモドキだろ？
Aren’t you just a false minoshiro?
機種 および型番をお尋ねでしたら
自走型アーカイブ
If you are inquiring my model and version,
I am an automotive archive of the SE778H Lambda autonomous evolution version.
自律進化バージョンＳＥ778Ｈ
ラムダです
ちょっと待って 何 言ってんの？
Hey, slow down.
What are you talking about?
本は どこにあるのよ？
Where are the books?
All paper-based printed interfaces
have either chemically decomposed
紙媒体に印字された
インターフェイスは
すでに ほとんどが酸化して
朽ち果てたか
戦乱および破壊行為によって
焼尽されたために
or have been lost to war and other destructive activities.
None are confirmed to remain.
現在 存在は確認されていません
Then you’re an empty library?
だったら
あんたは空っぽの図書館なの？
すべての情報は アーカイブに
搭載されている
All archived information has been stored as 890 petabytes of holographic memory.
容量890ペタバイトの
ホログラフィック記憶デバイスに
収められています
もし あんたが
わざと難しい言葉を使って
Are you using difficult words just to confuse us?
けむに巻こうとしてるんだったら
やっぱり それを全部
引き抜いた方がいいわね
Maybe I should tear them all off, after all.
全ての書籍の内容は
The files of all writings are recorded on a storage device inside me
私の内部にある記憶装置に
保存されており
and can be accessed at any time.
随時 呼び出しが可能です
それって…
いつでも読めるってこと？
Does that mean we can read them anytime we want?
おっしゃるとおりです
Correct.
じゃあ…
So, for example…
例えば…
Nakisou na aoringo kakaeteru mune no oku
泣きそうな青リンゴ  抱えてる胸の奥
In my chest, I carry a green apple that wets my eyes
Korogatte tsuyogatte
転がって  強がって
I fall over yet pretend to be strong
Kyuukutsu na sora niramu
窮屈な空睨む
I glower at the sky and it seems to suffocate me
Unmei ni juujun ni
運命に従順に
Do I look like I'd wait quietly
Jukusu no wo matsu mon ka
熟すのを待つもんか
For destiny to ripen it?
Sen no kaze
千の風
The winds
Agaite sakende
あがいて  叫んで
I struggle and scream
Fuke fuke
吹け吹け
Blow and blow
Watashi wa shabondama
わたしはしゃぼん玉
I'm a soap bubble
Soredemo shinjiteru
それでも信じてる
And still I have faith
Yokisenu arashi ni
予期せぬ  嵐に
In a sudden storm
Joushou shite kakou shite
上昇して  下降して
I rise and fall
Aragau shabondama
あらがうしゃぼん玉
I fight, soap bubble that I am
Soredemo ikiteku
それでも生きてく
And still I live on
Hajikeru shunkan niji hanate
弾ける瞬間  虹、放て
I make a rainbow when I burst
現在は
その存在は確認されていませんが
The word “Fiend” was first used…
While their existence today cannot be confirmed,
Users of PK only had…
that they once existed is undisputed,
Even so, their destructive potential was sufficient to disrupt contemporary social order.
将来 再び誕生する可能性は
高いと思われます
and it is likely that they may emerge once again in the near future.
The political, philosophical, and
ethical conflicts resulting thereof…
世界の人々の中で
それまで眠っていた力が
Humanity started to awaken to their latent potential.
目覚め始めました
Bloody
History